<Document>
[color=#ff0000]You 16 years of age to play on this server. Any users suspected to be under 16 years of age will be banned until they are of age.[/color]

[color=#ff0000]Disconnecting from or ignoring/evading Admin-helps will result in an appeal only ban.[/color]

[color=#a4885c]0.0[/color] Server staff have the final say in arguments. If you disagree with their decision feel free to open a ticket over at our Discord.

[color=#ff0000]Core Rules[/color]

[color=#a4885c]1.1[/color] Be excellent to each other (don’t be a dick rule).

[color=#a4885c]1.2[/color] Make it fun for all involved (consider how you affect the round for others).

[color=#a4885c]1.2e[/color] If you’re unsure then ask. Ahelp to keep it discrete.

[color=#a4885c]1.3[/color] Respect the admins and other players, they’re people too.

[color=#a4885c]1.4[/color] Discrimination based on protected characteristics is not allowed IC or OOC.

[color=#a4885c]1.4e[/color] The exception to this rule is speciesism, mutations and abominations, in character only.

[color=#a4885c]1.5[/color] ERP or erotic roleplay is not allowed in any form. This server is 16+ so respect your fellow players.

[color=#a4885c]1.6[/color] These are English servers. Speak only English both in and out of character.

[color=#a4885c]1.7[/color] Don't use exploits or external programs to play, gain an advantage, or disrupt/crash the round/server. This includes autoclickers and scripts to automate the game or evade AFK detection. Intentionally attempting to lag/crash the server will result in an immediate appeal-only ban.

[color=#ff0000]Roleplay Rules[/color]

[color=#a4885c]2.1[/color] Follow role play etiquette, using in-character (IC) and out-of-character (OOC) correctly, using proper text speech and an appropriate name.

[color=#a4885c]2.2[/color] Respect the lore/canon of this server. Read up or ask questions if needed for clarity or permission.

[color=#a4885c]2.3[/color] Creatures taken over by player characters should act accordingly to their role and that creatures intelligence.

[color=#a4885c]2.4[/color] Roleplay a character that fits the universe. You aren't the protagonist however so bear that in mind and play your background accordingly. No actual character names from the games or names of real life celebrities.

[color=#a4885c]2.5[/color] Characters that are part of a faction must act in benefit of their faction. You may not betray your faction without a really good reason! You may not aid another faction at the expense of your own without a justified cause!

[color=#a4885c]2.6[/color] Characters that leave a faction may not join another faction if said factions are rivals. This is for immersion's sake, no one would trust them not being spies. Following this same logic avoid re-writing a character's backstory to be in a different faction. We advise making a new character if you want to play in a different faction, there are 15 character slots for every player.

[color=#ff0000]Meta Rules[/color]

[color=#a4885c]3.1[/color] Metagrudging or harassing or killing someone who harmed you in a previous life or round is not allowed.

[color=#a4885c]3.2[/color] Meta communication is also banned. Don’t use VC or other means to communicate IC or current round information to others.

[color=#a4885c]3.3[/color] Don't blur the lines between IC and OOC. Keep them strictly separate and remember rule 1.1.

[color=#ff0000]No Fun Rules[/color]

[color=#a4885c]4.1[/color] Avoid loot hoarding, this is primarily a roleplay game, PvE and PvP come second. Players should generally work together to further the joint efforts of all involved and not focus solely on themselves.

[color=#a4885c]4.2[/color] Confrontation does not need to end in a firefight. This one should be obvious, not everything needs to be or turn into PvP. Let things influence your character, let people get away. Create conflict, create roleplay, do not play to win, play to have fun.

[color=#a4885c]4.2e[/color] Follow escalation rules:
    - You can defend yourself to the extent of protecting your own life, your allies (or the innocent).
    - You can defend your own property, theft is a crime and you have the right to stop it from happening.
    - If you attempt to roleplay as a raider try to mug people, shooting should not be the first thing you do.
    - Adminhelp the situation if you think someone is over-escalating.

[color=#a4885c]4.3[/color] Blitzkrieg rushing, or "bum-rushing" a major faction is no fun for most people and is forbidden. You have to remember this is a roleplaying game. We kindly ask that if you wish to attack one of the major factions that you first A-help and see if there is an admin available and talk to them first. If no admin is currently available avoid directly attacking a faction's base without proper reason, but if you end up attacking them for one reason or another please still send a message to the admin help panel that you're doing it and why. If the faction has been doing things that warrant it, such as "taxing" your town, or "attacking" your citizens you may take action against them. 

[color=#a4885c]4.3e[/color] Faction bases (including the town, tribal camp and caravan station beside the others) are off limits from being assaulted / robbed if they're empty - aka no living members of said faction are present in the current round.

[color=#a4885c]4.4[/color] Abusing or exploiting the lack of real intelligence of hostile NPC mobs in ways that it breaks immersion is not permitted. You likely ruin your own fun by "cheesing" the fight, in-fact you take opportunity from others to fight them fair and square.
</Document>
