<Document>
# Farming / Botany
A farmers role is to grow food for their community or to be sold via traders. Plant produce can be ground or juiced to make various extracts, used in cooking, eaten whole or used in a variety of crafting recipes.

# Tools
There are many tools that can be used to keep your crops healthy and growing. Most Wastelanders will use soil patches or planters for growing crops.

## Soil
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14Soil"/>
</Box>
Soil can be made in the crafting menu with <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14CompostRotted"/>
Soil is the most basic form of farming and won't give you any visual indicators like flags or lights to the status of the plants, so you need to examine them to see their status.

The lifecycle of a plant is the following:
- [color=lightgreen]Empty[/color]: no water, seed or nutrients
- [color=lightgreen]Hydrated[/color]: you've added water to it (e.g. from a bottle or bucket).
- [color=lightgreen]Ready for planting[/color]: you've added water and nutrients to it (i.e. fertilizer).
- [color=lightgreen]Planted[/color]: you've added a seed or clipping to it.
- [color=lightgreen]Ready for Harvest[/color]: you've waited for the plant to grow.
- [color=lightgreen]Sampled[/color]: you've taken a sample (seed/clipping)
- [color=lightgreen]Harvested[/color]: you've picked ready plants. Some plants will then grow again. Others will die and need replanting.
- [color=lightgreen]Unhealthy[/color]: You've sampled too many seeds or sprayed it with deadly chemicals. The plant isn't coping too well. It'll continue to grow. Health can be restored by fertilizers or you can cut your losses and extract a seed (plant clippers) and replant.
- [color=lightgreen]Old / Wilted[/color]: the plant has matured and will soon die. It will still be harvestable and you can extract seeds but only for a short duration. Extract the seed and then pluck it out / chop it down.
- [color=lightgreen]Dead[/color]: the plant has been harvested and ceased growing. It should be plucked out / chopped down. No seeds can be extracted.

## Planters
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14HydroponicsPlanter"/>
</Box>
Planters are a more advanced way of farming as it introduces visual flags as to the status of the plants growing in it. Everything is as with soil except now you get the following flags for plant status:
- [color=red]Red Flag, bottom right[/color]: Dead plant that needs re-planting. Use a spade to remove the plant.
- [color=orange]Weeds[/color]: The environment is sub-optimal. Check what is affecting the plant by Shift Clicking on it. It is likely weeds but it could be undesirable pressure or lack of oxygen. If weeds, use a mini hoe or spray 1 time with weed spray. Be warned, however, that overuse of weed killers can lead to unhealthy plants, possibly killing them.
- [color=#0336ff]Blue Flag, bottom left[/color]: Needs water. Use bucket on the water tank and fill the tray.
- [color=green]Green Flag, top left[/color]: Ready for harvest. Left click to harvest.
- [color=yellow]Yellow Flag, top right/color]: Needs nutrients. Use any fruit and put it into the soil or get fertilizer from animal dung or mining.


# Plant Genetics
Like all other forms of life, plants pass traits to offspring in their genes. By manipulating plant genetics, botanists can produce plant varieties with desirable mutations that increase plant health and yield.

## Traits
The phenotype, or set of observable characteristics and traits of a plant, can be determined through careful observation and study. A few common traits include:

- [color=lightgreen]Bioluminescence[/color]: plants with this trait glow in the dark
- [color=lightgreen]High yield[/color]: plants with this trait yield more fruit per harvest
- [color=lightgreen]Less water[/color]: plants with this trait require less water than normal to grow
- [color=lightgreen]Ligneous[/color]: plants with this trait require sharp tools to harvest
- [color=lightgreen]Long life[/color]: plants with this trait live for more harvest cycles before dying
- [color=lightgreen]Low light[/color]: plants with this trait need less light than normal to grow
- [color=lightgreen]Pest resistance[/color]: plants with this trait are more resistant to pests
- [color=lightgreen]Seedless[/color]: plants with this trait do not produce viable seeds
- [color=lightgreen]Weed resistance[/color]: plants with this trait suppress weed growth

You can determine the phenotype of a plant simply by growing them and observing them! This is how Gregor Mendel, father of genetics, studied them in 1866.

## Mutations
Plants treated with [color=cyan]unstable mutagen[/color] will experience random genetic mutations, which can alter their genes and result in changes to their traits. You can save the plants with mutations you want by harvesting their seeds.

The more unstable mutagen you use, the more mutations you will get. Since many genes are vital to a plant's survival, most mutations will cause a plant to die.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="UnstableMutagenChemistryBottle"/>
</Box>

## Cross-Pollination
You can use a [color=cyan]sterile swab[/color] to transfer pollen from one plant to another. Plants that are cross-pollinated have a chance to transfer traits. Be careful re-using swabs; pollen is sticky!

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BoxMouthSwab"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DiseaseSwab"/>
</Box>

## Chemicals
Some chemicals have special effects on plants.

<GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="Fertilizer"/>
Compost is also a source of fertilizer and is produced by letting animal dung rot away which takes around 5 minutes. Compost will also dissolve away after 2 minutes.

</Document>
