# Crafting System Guide

Welcome to the Crafting System Guide! This guide will help you understand how to create items using blueprints, workbenches, and various tools. Crafting is an essential part of survival in the wasteland.

Let’s dive into the details!

## Crafting Basics

Crafting is the process of creating items using blueprints, resources, and tools. Each blueprint specifies the required materials, tools, and workbench needed to craft the item. Here’s how it works:

1. Blueprints: Blueprints are the instructions for crafting. They specify the required resources, tools, and workbench type. Without a blueprint, you cannot craft an item.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14ClothingOuterPowerArmorT45Blueprint"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14WeaponSniper556TribalBlueprint"/>
</Box>
2. Workbenches: Different items require different workbenches. For example, a power armor blueprint might require a Power Armor Station.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14WorkbenchStation"/>
</Box>
3. Resources: You’ll need specific resources to craft items. These can include raw materials, junk components, or even other crafted items.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14ScrapElectronic"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14JunkGunpartsAdvancedFrame"/>
</Box>
4. Tools: Some recipes require tools like screwdrivers, wrenches, or welders. These tools are not consumed during crafting but are necessary to complete the process.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14Screwdriver"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14Welder"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14Wrench"/>
</Box>
5. Faction Restrictions: Some blueprints are only available to specific factions. Make sure you have the right faction alignment to access certain recipes.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14DecorationFlagNCR"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14FlagWallWesternBrotherhood"/>
</Box>


## Crafting Process

Here’s a step-by-step guide to crafting an item:

1. Find a Blueprint: Blueprints can be found in the world, purchased from traders, or earned as rewards. Each blueprint specifies the item it creates and the requirements for crafting.

2. Gather Resources: Check the blueprint for the required resources and gather them. You’ll need the exact amount specified.

3. Locate the Workbench: Find the appropriate workbench for the recipe. For example, a Power Armor Station is needed for power armor recipes.


Happy crafting, wastelander! With the right blueprints, tools, and resources, you can create powerful items to help you survive and thrive in the harsh world.