<Document>
# All Materials

This is a list of -all- materials available.

## Natural and Animal Products
Water is a valuable resource in Nuclear14. You'll often find dirty or irradiated water in the Wasteland which must be cleaned and purified in order to get clean drinking water.
  <GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="Water"/>
  <GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="WaterDirty"/>
  <GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="WaterIrradiated"/>
Filtering dirty water with charcoal creates <GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="WaterFiltered"/>. Heat this to near boiling to obtain clean <GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="Water"/>. Boiling <GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="WaterSalt"/> yields <GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="TableSalt"/>.
Radscorpion Tails can be butchered from Radscorpions with a knife and are used to produce <GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="Antidote"/>.
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14MaterialRadscorpionTail"/>
Fire Ants can provide <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14FoodFireantNectar"/> which contains <GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="N14FireAntNectar"/> for teas.

Brahmin Hide, hides and chitins are butchered off their respective animals.
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14MaterialBrahminHide"/>

For all other drinks and drink related products see the Bartending page.

## Ores, Metals and Derivatives
Mine lead ore and process it at a forge to get lead ingots.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14LeadOre"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14IngotLead"/>
</Box>

If you break some objects, you will get a small amount of materials.
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14WreckSportscar"/>
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14ScrapLead"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14ScrapSteel"/>
</Box>
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14ComputerTerminalRustedRigged"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14JunkTV"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14ScrapCopper"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14ScrapElectronic"/>
</Box>

Mine sulfur ore and process it at a forge to get sulfur powder.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SulfurOre"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SulfurPowder"/>
</Box>

Mine Fertilizer ore from rocks and grind it to get fertilizer as a reagent.
<Box>
<GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="Fertilizer"/>
</Box>

Combine Fertilizer, Sulfur Powder and Carbon (from coal) to produce gunpowder.
<Box>
<GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="Gunpowder"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Gunpowder"/>
</Box>

## Wood and Wood Derivatives
Wood planks can be crafted from wooden logs, obtained from trees. This can then be crafted into paper, and paper into cardboard.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MaterialWoodPlank1"/>
</Box>

## Other Materials
Plastic can be obtained by melting down pre-war scrap made of plastic using a welder, by making it in a chemical reaction or by using a recycler if you can find one.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SheetPlastic"/>
</Box>

## Pre-War Products
Mr Handy fuel can be found by scavenging the Wasteland and is a handy source of fuel for welders and generators.
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14FuelTankHandy"/>
</Document>

