<Document>

 # Local Ranks, Positions & Titles

This expedition is led by a group of senior Paladins who are commonly referred to as “[color=#E9D28E]Paladin Lords[/color]” as they rule over all who reside in their bunkers at any given time. It’s not uncommon for these Paladins to be landholders back at the homelands.

Below them do the more junior [color=#E9D28E]Paladins[/color] reside, who generally function as field team leaders and heavy infantry. But do not be mistaken each and every one of these warriors earned their place through merit (or maybe blood).

[color=#E9D28E]Knights[/color] are the main line of light infantry and the bulk of Brotherhood forces, generally they are properly trained and experienced but that still doesn’t mean that they should be deployed by themselves. Strength is in numbers. They are often encouraged to find other professions due an old directive issued during relative peacetime, this was mostly beneficial to take some weight off from the shoulders of Scribes.

[color=#E9D28E]Initiates[/color] are the fresh blood of the chapter, they’re errand boys and carriers of the Paladins’ burdens while they’re still learning about the values of the chapter. They are often advised to simply obey all instructions from other members with more experience.

[color=#E9D28E]Scribes[/color] have various duties in the chapter, among many other things they might function like mechanics, medical officers, or researchers of various subjects. They are responsible for documentation and holding ceremonies too. Scribes are part of the civilian arm of the Brotherhood, making them stand outside the normal chain of command and able to ignore those who are not in charge of their outpost or have seniority over them in their respective departments.

[color=#9AB9BE]Squire and Senior Knight are purely veterancy roles for roleplay purposes through unlocking of items in the Loadouts. Similarly to that you may freely claim that your character is a more junior or senior member of the Brotherhood (or in their current position within the Brotherhood) based on their background.[/color]

</Document>
