<Document>

 # Midwestern Brotherhood
[color=#ADCCA0]Playable faction![/color]

The Midwestern Brotherhood of Steel is a vast feudal empire ranging from Colorado to Illinois, but here in this state they’re nothing more than a recon force. Their goal in the region is investigating the sudden rise of several other powers (namely the Washington chapter & RCMP) while collecting technology - if they can afford the time to do so.

Almost a century ago - during the war with the Calculator - this chapter was able to put their hands on a machine army, further solidifying their rule over the Midwest. They trained tribals while building military outposts, large irrigation networks and cities. They do not fear sharing their technology as long as that benefits them, their core tenants claim that educating the people can lead to a safer world. Discrimination towards mutates was outlawed in their holdings and heavily punished, these former outcasts have become valued members of society. The Brotherhood became guardians of the lands under their watchful eyes, or at least that’s how they’re seen by their sympathisers. But those who stood in their ways were severely punished. The Midwestern Brotherhood believes in collective punishment and making examples of outlaws, even going so far to have deathcamps or crucify misfits to install fear in their subjects.

Today the chapter is desperately trying to justify its own existence by launching expeditions to countless places outside their core territories to project power and maybe find something to strengthen themselves, but the truth is that they’re spread way too thin and likely their rule over the Wastelands is coming to an end.

[color=#9AB9BE]Generally the MBoS has everything they need for a quite luxurious gameplay, including food, clean water, medicine and powerful firearms with decent armour. Their combat style is similar to the WBoS’ with heavy infantry and light infantry wildly separated but with more flexibility and slightly less armour value. It’s highly encouraged to use your Paladins like living shields or shocktroops.[/color]

[color=#BF7263]The regime of the Midwestern Brotherhood is brutal and physical punishments of disobeying personnel are permitted, even summary executions on the spot in extreme cases.[/color]

</Document>
