<Document>

 # New California Republic
[color=#ADCCA0]Playable faction![/color]

A revival of the pre-war United States’ government. The NCR are a civilised yet corrupt nation looking to expand their ideals across the Wasteland. They are dedicated to old-world values of democracy and the rule of law. Their citizens can enjoy clean water, electricity and education. But this, Washington, is not the Republic.

Originating from an ancient Vault and the now capital city of Shady Sands the New California Republic promises freedom to its citizens. In the early days these were true promises, people were able to access free education, affordable healthcare and the roads were kept safe. But as the NCR grew so did its needs, they expanded in every direction possible and often forcefully by annexing settlements without even asking them if they desire to be a part of anything. Today if we include every town and ranch they have millions of citizens, but the services granted by the states to the residents greatly have degraded alongside the road security.

The NCR forces in the region have several goals of course: they wish to expand the borders of their state by convincing local settlements to join, they too are hunting the same relics the Washington Brotherhood is after and of course they would like to engage in diplomatic talks with the Midwestern Brotherhood due to rumors of them having mutual enemies in Arizona. None of these missions is going well at this time, but that might change.

 - The first NCR forces that entered Oregon and Washington were Rangers, who were “exiled” away for this task shortly after the Unification Treaty in 2271. Those who were sent here were almost exclusively rogue elements - who the NCR Army’s High Command didn’t want around - and a few talented volunteers who wished to explore the northern regions. Their task was gathering intelligence on the region when they arrived and now they are as scouts, sabotours & vigilantes.

 - A year later - in 2272 - the 3rd Airborne Battalion, aka the White Bears, followed and began establishing makeshift outposts using intelligence gathered by the first recon forces of the Rangers. Their task was swiftly inserting into the region and ensuring that additional forces may more easily move in. The White Bears are of course a very elite force, each and every one of them is trained to be able to use parachutes. Additionally many of them are capable pilots of various aircrafts; let those be cargo transports, vertibirds or attack planes for close air support.

 - Less than a year ago - in 2274 - the 7th Infantry Regiment, aka Roachrats, marched across Washington to reinforce the airborne elders of theirs. The Roachrats are a new unit composed of NCR Army personnel who were heavily disliked by their higher ups, performed really badly in basic training or were recruited from conscripts. But they brought tools of real fortification with them to strengthen the foothold around here.

[color=#9AB9BE]It’s highly recommended to stay in groups led by Sergeants to maximise effectiveness and ensure safety of all units. This faction’s soldiers are quite fragile due to their armour, they should overwhelm the enemy with sheer numbers or use superior tactics whenever possible.[/color]

[color=#BF7263]Playing as an undesirable “rogue” Ranger or a member of the Roachrats does NOT permit you to betray your faction in combat or go AWOL.[/color]

</Document>
