<Document>

 # The Townsfolk
[color=#ADCCA0]Playable faction![/color]

The Townsfolk are the inhabitants of  the local centre of civilisation, just trying to survive and maybe improve their lives through farming, scavenging and trade. Larger factions have recently set their eyes on the town and it's up to the Mayor how they lead their people under these new external pressures.

As stated above the settlement is led by a [color=#E9D28E]Mayor[/color], who might be new or did their duty for decades - it’s really difficult to keep up with all these small towns around. Some Mayors are elected democratically while others purchase their way into the position as successful merchants, and a few organise hostile takeovers by force.

Generally most people don’t want to deal with politics on a day-to-day basis, meaning that most Mayors rule for life and with unrestricted authority. The various settlements of the region only tend to hold elections when the previous leader of their town has perished, one way or another.

The [color=#E9D28E]Town’s Guard[/color] is led by a [color=#E9D28E]Marshall[/color], this person is responsible to keep order within the walls of the settlement and the protection of the Townsfolk. Some of the Guard might be more loyal to the Mayor while others are ideologically aligned with their homes’ residents.

[color=#9AB9BE]While playing as Townsfolk, sticking together and having social events to keep up morale is paramount as you have no access to powerful kits or rich armouries. Your life depends on your trust in the Town’s Guard and the Mayor’s leadership skills[/color], [color=#BF7263]later of which might be opposed anytime if sufficient reasons are given.[/color]

[color=#BF7263]As a Town’s Guard you have to remain loyal to at least the people of the town or the Mayor separately, if not both. Your character can be corrupt and look the other way when dealing with petty criminals, but must protect the settlement in great times of need.[/color]

</Document>
