<Document>

 # Washington Brotherhood
[color=#ADCCA0]Playable faction![/color]

The Washington Brotherhood of Steel is a rising power of the region and was formed two decades ago when their current Elder and his followers left Lost Hills due ideological differences. This group believes that a great cataclysm is once again on the horizon and only through the usage of previously locked away and forgotten technologies may humankind survive.

Their core belief is that the next apocalypse might be fatal for humankind and for such reasons the men have to be “upgraded” using machinery and genetic augmentations whenever possible. As people progress through the ranks of their chapter they tend to either start looking more and more healthy due to genetic enhancements, or more and more like a machine due to cybernetic implants. They are generally not opposed towards taking on new members from outside, but they have to be already skilled and talented as they’re only interested in the best. Similarly they are able to tolerate mutates and ghouls as long as they’re useful. The majority of the chapter believes that many of the “uglies” can be good cannon fodder to keep their actually valuable soldiers out of harm’s way, while ancient ghouls might even hold the wisdom & technical knowledge of centuries.

These days this Brotherhood - like many others - is still slowly but steadily growing, establishing new bunkers and attempting to justify its own existence by continuously finding new enemies and labelling them as the bringers of the dark ages, but maybe they themselves will be the cause behind the next fall of humankind. In the meantime they have to carefully maneuver the dangerous political games of the North and only spend lives when that’s necessary.

[color=#9AB9BE]Generally the WBoS has everything they need for a quite luxurious gameplay, including food, clean water, medicine and powerful firearms with decent armour. Their combat style is similar to the MBoS’ with heavy infantry and light infantry wildly separated but with slightly better armour values and a bit less flexibility. It’s highly encouraged to use your Paladins like living shields or shocktroops.[/color]

[color=#BF7263]The regime of the Washington Brotherhood is brutal and physical punishments of disobeying personnel are permitted, even “repurposing surgeries” in extreme cases.[/color]

</Document>
