<Document>

 # Lost Hills Brotherhood
[color=#BF7263]Background lore faction![/color]
 
The original Brotherhood, which was led by the first Elder - Roger Maxson - and the ancestral home of many other chapters before they split away. They were weakened by awful internal and external politics for many years now. But they still stand and are able to support a handful of other chapters on missions far away from the old California, if they show loyalty to Lost Hills and its beliefs. Today they are not in a state to directly oppose the New California Republic - which surrounds them - but one day they might regain their former glory.
There are countless chapters of the Brotherhood of Steel across the Wastelands of the former United States of America (& beyond). The most important to the lands of the former Washington state are the cleverly named Washington Brotherhood and the Midwestern Brotherhood.

 - The Washington chapter’s leaders exiled themselves from Lost Hills roughly two decades ago due to ideological differences about the usage of dangerous technologies for the Brotherhood’s own gains. They believed that continuing human biological research (mostly consisting of FEV experiments) and heavily augmenting people with cybernetics is righteous as long as it’s done to enhance their own “Protectors of The World” in these trying times. Lost Hills not daring to risk a civil war and losing countless soldiers have permitted them to leave and go north. Lost Hills has a very tense relation with this chapter, but they might communicate and provide minor assistance to one another in the form of supply transports, sharing strategic intelligence or technological knowledge.

 - The Midwestern chapter’s original members were sent east to chase down remnants of the Master’s Army, but the truth is that it was an exilement due to another ideological difference. This conflict was centered around Lost Hills’ refusal to take on new members from outside and share even (relatively) harmless technology & knowledge with the people of the Wastelands. This happened roughly eighty years ago and since relations have worsened to such a state that all communications were ceased between Lost Hills and them.

</Document>
