<Document>
[color=#ff0000]YOU MUST BE AT LEAST 16 YEARS OF AGE TO PLAY ON THIS SERVER. ANY USERS SUSPECTED OF BEING UNDER 16 YEARS OF AGE WILL BE BANNED UNTIL THEY ARE OF AGE.[/color]

[color=#ff0000]DISCONNECTING FROM OR IGNORING/EVADING ADMIN-HELPS WILL RESULT IN AN APPEAL ONLY BAN.[/color]

This is the "short" form of the rules, which has all the information any regular player should need. You can find the "long" form of the rules with more examples & clarifications of any ambiguity in our guidebooks > administration section, should you need it.

[color=#ff0000]Core Rules[/color]

[color=#a4885c]1.1[/color] Be excellent to each other (don’t be a dick rule).

[color=#a4885c]1.2[/color] Make it fun for all involved (consider how you affect the round for others).

[color=#a4885c]1.2e[/color] If you’re unsure then ask. ahelp to keep it discrete.

[color=#a4885c]1.3[/color] Respect the admins and other players, they’re people too.

[color=#a4885c]1.4[/color] Discrimination based on protected characteristics is not allowed IC or OOC.

[color=#a4885c]1.4e[/color] The exception to this rule is speciesism, mutations and abominations, in character only.

[color=#a4885c]1.5[/color] ERP or erotic roleplay is not allowed in any form. This server is 16+ so respect your fellow players.

[color=#a4885c]1.6[/color] These are English servers. Speak only English in IC and OOC.

[color=#a4885c]1.7[/color] Don't use exploits or external programs to play, gain an advantage, or disrupt/crash the round/server. This includes autoclickers and scripts to automate the game or evade AFK detection. Intentionally attempting to lag/crash the server will result in an immediate appeal-only ban.

[color=#ff0000]Roleplay Rules[/color]

[color=#a4885c]2.1[/color] Follow role play etiquette, using in-character (IC) and out-of-character (OOC) correctly, using proper text speech and an appropriate name.

[color=#a4885c]2.2[/color] Respect the lore/canon. Read up or ask questions if needed for clarity or permission.

[color=#a4885c]2.3[/color] Creatures taken over by player characters should act accordingly to their role and that creatures intelligence. Feral animals won't dodge bullets.

[color=#a4885c]2.4[/color] Roleplay a character that fits the universe. You aren't the protagonist however so bear that in mind and play your background accordingly. No actual character names from the games.

[color=#ff0000]Meta Rules[/color]

[color=#a4885c]3.1[/color] Metagrudging or harassing or killing someone who harmed you in a previous life or round is not allowed.

[color=#a4885c]3.2[/color] Meta communication is also banned. Don’t use VC or other means to communicate IC or current round information to others.

[color=#a4885c]3.3[/color] Don't blur the lines between IC and OOC. Keep them strictly separate and remember rule 1.1.

[color=#ff0000]No Fun Rules[/color]

[color=#a4885c]4.1[/color] Avoid loot hoarding, this is a PvE game mode and not a PvP game mode. Players should work together to further the joint efforts of all involved and not focus solely on themselves.

[color=#a4885c]4.2[/color] Conforntration does not need to end in a firefight. This one should be obvious, not everything needs to be or turn into PvP. Let things influence your character, let people get away. Create conflict, create roleplay, do not play to win, play to have fun.

[color=#a4885c]4.2e[/color] Follow escalation rules:
    - You can defend yourself to the extent of protecting your own life.
    - Don't outright leave people to die if you get in a fight, make an effort to heal them or bring them to people.
    - Adminhelp the situation if you think someone is over-escalating.
	- See the full escalation rules in the guidebook.
</Document>
