<Document>
# Factions

Nuclear14 has a large number of roles and factions, some more important and prevelant than others:

## Main Factions

### NCR
A revival of the US Government, the NCR are a civilised military democracy looking to expand their ideals across the Wasteland. Their role here is to try encourage the Townsfolk to join the NCR.

### Townsfolk
The Townsfolk are the local inhabitants of the area and are the local centre of civilisation, just trying to get by and improve their lives through farming, scavenging and trade.

Larger factions have recently set their eyes on the town and it's up to the Mayor how they lead their people under these new external pressures.

### Tribes
The Tribes of the local area have an important part to play in keeping the local ecology in balance. They are led by a Tribal Elder who decides on the culture, ideals and attitude of the tribe.
Be it traditional or forward thinking, passive or aggressive, isolationist or ready to join the fold of the city and trade.

### Vault Dwellers
The local Vault Dwellers are largely unknown to the surface inhabitants. The location of the Vault mostly lost to time. The Vault Dwellers live in harmony beneath the surface waiting for the day the door might open.
The Vault is lead by the Overseer which unbeknown to the Dwellers, may have an objective or experiment to carry out. The Vault may also have a key component fail at any time forcing them to react and adapt, possibly opening the door for help.

### Caravan Company
The Caravan Company are the main source of new resources and equipment in the Wasteland. They have the supply lines setup to trade long distances which is especially useful once the local resources start to dry up.
The CC are a non aggressive faction. They may store valuables in their warehouses and might strike a deal with the NCR for additional protection in exchange for supply routes.
If the CC are lost or destroyed, the railway station supply point will cease to function.

### Washington Brotherhood of Steel
The Washington Brotherhood of Steel are an outcast branch of the BOS, descended from a Midwest Brotherhood expedition who lost contact. They are the most formidable local force in our Wasteland and are a purist faction who hate mutations.

They have technological objectives and are known for kidnapping. They try to operate undetected but have immense firepower should they need to use it.

### Midwest Brotherhood of Steel
The Midwest Brotherhood of Steel are another splinter organisation from the original Brotherhood. They have different values and are known to recruit locals into the faction to achieve their goals, this includes tribals, ghouls and mutants.

The Midwest BOS in this setting are scouting out the area in search of their original lost patrols which later became the Washington BOS. They are scouting and keeping a low profile and avoid confrontation.

</Document>
