<Document>
# Factions

Nuclear14 has a large number of roles and factions, some more important and prevelant than others:

## New California Republic
A revival of the US Government, the NCR are a civilized democracy looking to expand their ideals across the Wasteland. They are dedicated to old-world values of democracy and the rule of law. Their role here is to try to encourage the Townsfolk to join the NCR, and investigate other major factions of the region.

One must not forget about the Rangers of the NCR, who roam the Wasteland and attempt to serve justice to the common folk.

## The Townsfolk
The Townsfolk are the local inhabitants of the area and are the local centre of civilisation, just trying to survive and maybe improve their lives through farming, scavenging and trade.
Larger factions have recently set their eyes on the town and it's up to the Mayor how they lead their people under these new external pressures.

## The Tribes
The Tribes of the local area have an important part to play in keeping the local ecology in balance. They are led by a Tribal Elder who decides on the culture, ideals, and attitude of the tribe.
Be it traditional or forward thinking, passive or aggressive, isolationist or ready to join the city and engage in trade.

## The Vault
The local Vault remains largely unfamiliar to the surface dwellers, just as the surface is also largely secreted away to those within the Vault. The location of the Vault mostly lost to time. This underground sanctuary is lead by the Overseer who, unbeknownst to the Dwellers, may have an objective or experiment to carry out.

## Caravan Company
The Blue Line Co. is the main source of new resources and equipment in this region of the Wasteland. They have the supply lines set up to trade long distances which is especially useful once the local resources start to dry up. The company itself originates from Canada, but they still accept bottlecaps and NCR dollars because their caravans trade far and wide.
If the local Blue Line station is lost or destroyed, the railway station will very likely cease to function.

## Midwestern Brotherhood
The Midwestern Brotherhood of Steel are another splinter organisation from the original Brotherhood of Steel. This land is not their home, but they're here on a mission to investigate the rumors about this region's vast supplies of advanced technologies and gather intelligence on the new Washington chapter of the Brotherhood.

About 80 years ago, they departed from Lost Hills and established a feudal empire in their new territories. They are open to sharing its technology with their subjects if it also serves their interests. Recruiting tribals and training them is a common occurance back home, but should they continue doing that this far away? Should they trust the locals here?

## Washington Brotherhood
The Washington Brotherhood of Steel is a new and rising power within this region. They self-exiled from Lost Hills just a few years back. The intention of their Elder is finding the truth to the legends surrounding various advanced technologies of the former Washington state. They are an isolationist military dictatorship and came here with the intent to grow in strength while hiding in the shadows.

Their senior members sense that a storm is coming that could wipe out the entire Brotherhood - maybe humankind - and because of this they are not afraid of utilizing more dangerous & extreme technologies, knowledge that other chapters' Elders would advise to destroy. Due to this radical ideology of theirs they are no longer welcome back at Lost Hills.

</Document>
